Hi, I'm Eadin from the Open Learning Initiative.
cue-2
In this video, I'm going to show you
cue-3
how to add and configure OLI Torus
cue-4
in your Canvas course step-by-step.
cue-5
Let's get started.
cue-6
The first thing you need to do
cue-7
when integrating Torus to Canvas
cue-8
is to ensure that OLI Torus is
cue-9
registered as an LTI Advantage Tool in
cue-10
your institution's Canvas system.
cue-11
This is typically handled by a Canvas
cue-12
administrator. If your Canvas admin hasn't
cue-13
integrated OLI Torus yet, contact OLI support
cue-14
at oli-help@cmu.edu.
cue-15
Okay. Now, to place the OLI Torus link to Canvas,
cue-16
you have three options,
cue-17
the navigation menu, an assignment, or a module.
cue-18
Adding OLI Torus to the navigation
cue-19
menu is recommended if you and students
cue-20
need to enter it frequently.
cue-21
This will result in OLI Torus also being visible
cue-22
on the Canvas class homepage.
cue-23
Adding OLI as an assignment
cue-24
is the recommended placement.
cue-25
This allows you to place OLI in
cue-26
your weekly curriculum and assign the
cue-27
reading as homework or out-of-class activities.
cue-28
Adding OLI Torus as a module
cue-29
will allow students to navigate to OLI
cue-30
through the module view.
cue-31
To avoid confusion, add your Torus course
cue-32
link in only one place, navigation menu,
cue-33
assignments, or modules.
cue-34
Option one, add the link to the navigation menu.
cue-35
Go to Settings at the bottom of the
cue-36
Canvas navigation menu.
cue-37
Click the Navigation tab on the top
cue-38
and scroll to find OLI Torus, not the other ones
cue-39
under Disabled Items. Drag it
cue-40
up to the list of enabled navigation items
cue-41
and click Save. OLI Torus will now appear
cue-42
in your course's left-hand menu.
cue-43
Option two, add the link in an assignment.
cue-44
Click Assignments. Add Assignment
cue-45
and add a title. This is what students
cue-46
will see when they click on Assignments in
cue-47
the Canvas class. Scroll down to
cue-48
Submission Type, select External Tool.
cue-49
Click Find. Choose OLI Torus from the list
cue-50
and click Load in a New Tab.
cue-51
Click Save and Publish or Save. If necessary,
cue-52
publish the OLI Torus assignment by clicking the
cue-53
Not Published icon on the right side of
cue-54
the page. Option three, add the link in a module.
cue-55
Click Modules in the nav menu. Then create
cue-56
a new module. Give the module a name such
cue-57
as OLI Torus Course, or base the title on
cue-58
your Torus content, and click Add Module.
cue-59
In the new module, click the plus
cue-60
sign and select External Tool.
cue-61
Select OLI Torus from the list. Update the
cue-62
title if you like. Click Load in a New
cue-63
Tab and click Add Item. Publish the OLI
cue-64
Torus module by clicking
cue-65
the Unpublished icon on the right end of
cue-66
the OLI Torus module.
cue-67
And once you've added the link to Canvas,
cue-68
it's time to configure your OLI Torus
cue-69
course materials for use with your students.
cue-70
Click the OLI Torus link you
cue-71
just added to load it in a new tab and
cue-72
configure your OLI Torus materials.
cue-73
Click Start and follow the prompts.
cue-74
Select a source material to base your course on.
cue-75
Use the search feature to find the desired
cue-76
content if necessary. Now enter basic
cue-77
info link, course name, course section
cue-78
number, can be a catalog number or CRN,
cue-79
for example, and modality for how class
cue-80
meets and other course details.
cue-81
Voila, your section has now been created.
cue-82
Note that once set up, all links will
cue-83
point to the same OLI Torus course no
cue-84
matter where students access it from in
cue-85
Canvas. Students have no OLI Torus accounts.
cue-86
They will access everything from
cue-87
the Canvas link.
cue-88
There you have it.
cue-89
In just a few steps, you can add and
cue-90
configure OLI Torus in your Canvas course.
cue-91
If you need to unlink a course, contact
cue-92
OLI support at oli-help@cmu.edu.